# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, I am Chef Wang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
Today I’m going to share with you a family-style dish
# 双色豆腐
Two-color Tofu
# 首先我们准备老豆腐1大块（约400克）
First, we prepare a piece of firm tofu (about 400 gram)
# 从中间切开之后重新叠在一起切成小正方形备用
Cut it half, pile together then cut it into cubes
# 准备猪血几块以同样的方法切成小正方形备用
Prepare a few pieces of pork blood and cut into cubes the same way
# 准备鲜牛肉100克切成小条之后剁碎备用
Prepare 100 gram of fresh beef, cut into strips then chop them
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next step, prepare the side ingredients
# 准备西红柿1个从中间切开
Prepare a tomato, cut it in half
# 然后再切成小粒备用
Then dice it
# 准备大蒜几颗拍散之后剁碎备用
Crush a few cloves of garlic, then chop them
# 准备小葱头几根切碎备用
Cut up some scallions
# 下一步开始制作
Next step, we start to cook
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
First, we add enough water to the wok
# 加入食用盐2勺
Add two spoon of salt
# 然后加入切好的猪血和豆腐下锅焯水1分钟
Then blench the pork blood and tofu for 1 minute
# 水开之后（锅）离火将豆腐浸泡1分钟
When the water boils, remove the wok from the flame, soak the tofu for another 1 minute
# 这一步的目的是让豆腐和猪血更嫩
The purpose is to make tofu and pork blood more tender
# 1分钟之后倒出控水备用
After a minute, take them out and drain out the water
# 下一步开始准备炒辅料
Next, we start to prepare the side ingredients
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
After wok is heated, add some oil to rinse the wok
# 滑好锅之后将热油倒出
pull out the hot oil after rinsing the wok
# 热油倒出之后加入适量的底油
Pull out the hot oil, then add some base oil
# 油温5成热之后将剁好的牛肉末下锅炒香爆干水份
When the oil is half heated up, put ground beef into the wok, cook it until it sweats out
# 牛肉爆香之后加入切好的蒜末和西红柿
After the beef smells down, add chopped garlic and tomato
# 然后转中小火将西红柿翻炒1分钟
Turn to mid-low heat and cook the tomato for a minute
# 这一步的目的是去除西红柿的酸味
The purpose is to get rid of the sourness from the tomato
# 西红柿炒香之后加入适量的清水
After the tomato is cooked, add some water
# 下一步开始调味
Next step is to season
# 锅中加入食用盐1勺（约3克）
Add a spoon of salt (about 3 gram) into the wok
# 加入少许的白糖
Add some white sugar
# 加入胡椒粉1克
Add 1 gram of white pepper powder
# 加入蚝油10克
Add 10 gram of oyster sauce
# 然后将焯好水的豆腐下锅烧3分钟
Then put the blenched tofu into the wok and cook for 3 minutes
# 烧至2分钟的时候加入适量的水淀粉勾成薄芡
After two minutes, add some slurry to thicken a little
# 然后烧至3分钟的时候再加入少许的水淀粉勾芡
After the third minute, add some more slurry to thicken into gravy
# 间隔勾芡2次可以防止成菜之后豆腐的水份溢出
Double thickening can prevent the water from the tofu spill all over after the dish is done
# 勾好芡之后再加入少许的明油即可出锅装盘
After thickening, add some Ming You (oil for a shiny presence), then decorate the dish
# 一道非常简单美味的双色豆腐就制作完成
A simple yet delicious “Two-color Tofu” is done
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，此菜可以加牛肉末或者猪肉末制作
# 第二，西红柿必须多翻炒几下去酸，否则成菜之后会有一股异常的酸味
# 第三，此菜不可添加鸡精味精，可以适当的多加一些蚝油调鲜味
# 双色豆腐的技术总结完毕
Conclusion
First, this dish can be cooked with either ground beef or ground pork
Second, the tomato has to be cooked longer to get rid of the sourness, or the dish will be weirdly sour
Thirdly, this dish should not add chicken bouillon, you can add more oyster sauce to increase the umami favor
That’s all for the conclusion of “Two-color Tofu”